Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Sigaux Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0000a
30 linear_feet
- Achard I Marcel Achard. Press clippings, correspondence (Marcel Achard to G. S., Juliette Achard to G. S.), one handwritten and several typed manuscripts with corrections, G. S. notes, biographical notecard, journal excerpts, publisher catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Achard II Marcel Achard. G. S. notecards (with première production information), G. S. notes, Achard chronology, individual folders for Achard's works, book and journal excerpts, periodical, press clippings, programs, bookstore/publisher catalog pages. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adamov 1908-1970 Arthur Adamov. Press clippings, transcripts (of radio shows), periodical, book and journal excerpts, biographical notecard, individual folders for Adamov's works. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albee Edward Albee. Press clippings, periodical, biographical notecard, journal excerpt, individual folders for Albee's works. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Anouilh I Jean Anouilh. Press clippings (general), journal excerpts, periodical, bookstore/publisher catalog pages and advertisements. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Anouilh II Jean Anouilh. Individual folders for Anouilh's works, press clippings, periodicals, programs, theater tickets, journal excerpts. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Antoine André Antoine. Press clippings, letters signed Francis Pruner, correspondence signed André Antoine, book catalog pages, typed manuscript (speech?), book and journal excerpts. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Arden John Arden. Press clippings, periodical, typed transcript (radio), book catalog page. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arout Gabriel Arout. Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, programs, periodicals, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio). (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Arrabal Fernando Arrabal. Press clippings, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts, Arrabal chronology, book advertisement. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Alain Auraita Alain. Press clippings, bibliography, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio), book advertisement and catalog pages, journal excerpts, handwritten note to G. S., periodical. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ambigu Le Théâtre de l'Ambigu (ou l'Ambigu-Comique). Press clippings, two printed booklets (dated 1834 and 1847). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Apollinaire Guillaume Apollinaire. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), journal excerpts, book advertisements and catalog pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Architectes Architects. Press clippings - mostly devoted to Le Corbusier. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Aron Raymond Aron. Press clippings, printed invitation, periodical, journal excerpt, book reviews/newsletters, book advertisement and catalog pages. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Artaud Antonin Artaud. Press clippings, bibliography, handwritten chronology, periodical, journal excerpts, book advertisement pages. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Audiberti Jacques Audiberti. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), 2 small books, individual folders for Audiberti's works, book and journal excerpts, program. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Balzac I Honoré de Balzac. Correspondence signed M. Bouteron, pamphlet about "Bedouck" (Société Balzacienne), book and journal articles by Marcel Bouteron, many handwritten notes (citations, bibliography, etc.). (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Balzac II Honoré de Balzac. Press clippings relating to Balzac and Balzacian Societies, typed transcript (radio), bookstore/publisher catalog with order form, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, 2 flyers ("Confraternité Universelle Balzacienne"). (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Balzac III Honoré de Balzac. Press clippings, professional correspondence relating to Sigaux's 3-article contribution to the Oeuvres Complètes Illustrées de Balzac, G. S. notes, typed manuscript with handwritten notes/corrections - on Balzac's Maratre, bookstore catalog pages, typed transcript (radio), typed explanation of the "Oeuvres" with instructions to the contributing authors, blank contribution forms, periodicals, journal and book excerpts. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Allemagne Germany. Indvidual folders covering German Theatre and its personalities, press clippings, typed transcipts (radio), G. S. notes, periodicals, book and journal excerpts, book advertisement and catalog pages, publisher's newsletter. A. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- A. XXe. Individual folders covering 20th Century German Theatre and its personalities, press clippings, programs, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes, periodicals, journal excerpts, book advertisement and catalog pages, playbills (typed and printed), letter (Pierre Garnier to G. S.). (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Autriche Austria. Individual folders covering Austrian Theatre and its personalities, press clippings, G. S. notes, journal excerpts, promotional flyer, book advertisement and catalog page, typed transcript (radio). (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Barrault Jean Louis Barrault. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement, card/note signed Barrault, program, includes a folder on Madeleine Renaud, typed transcript (radio), card/note signed by M. Renaud. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Barrault Jean Louis Barrault. Individual folders covering Barrault's work, press clippings, reviews, programs, journal excerpts. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Baty Gaston Baty. Press clippings, programs, G. S. note, typed transcript (speech), letter (official letter head, Henry de Madaillant to Paul Blanchart), book and journal excerpts, ticket and newsletters of the Association des Amis de Baty, folder with press clippings and a letter relating to Marguerite Jamois. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Beaumarchais Pierre Auguste Caron de Beaumarchais. Press clippings, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts, periodical, bookstore catalog page. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Becque Henry Becque. Press clippings, printed note cards (1927 -biography, bibliography, etc.), periodical, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Belgique Belgium. Press clippings, individual folders on Belgian Theatre and its personalities, typed transcripts (radio), typed program, periodical, book and journal excerpts, G. S. notes, bookstore catalog pages and advertisement, publication of Théâtre Royal du Gymnase from the '59-'60 season. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Billetdoux 1927 François Billetdoux. Press clippings, typed transcripts (radio and stage), cards, confidential/official correspondence (Billetdoux to G. S.), programs, periodical, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts, invitations/tickets to a special Press production. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bourdet Edward Bourdet. Press clippings, program, typed transcript (radio), periodical, individual folders for Bourdet's works, G. S. notes. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bourges - Monnet "la Comédie de Bourges" and Gabriel Monnet. Press clippings, typed transcript, program, typed schedule for the '64-'65 season, typed manuscript for the '65 program, publicity photos, publications from the "Bourges Maison de Culture". (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bourseiller Antoine Bourseiller. Press clippings. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Romain Bouteille Press clippings, programs, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, periodicals, typed script for a video production, correspondence (invitation to a dress rehearsal). (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Brassens Georges Brassens. Press clippings, periodicals, program. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Brecht 1 Bertolt Brecht. Press clippings, G. S. notes, typed transcript, printed biographical notecard. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Brecht 2 Bertolt Brecht. Press clippings, programs, playbill, G. S. notes, periodical, newsletter (Chaillot Théâtre National), book and journal excerpts, book advertisement page, typed transcript (radio). (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Brel: 1929-1978 Jacques Brel. Press clippings, programs, periodical, color photo. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Bryn Mawr Bryn Mawr College, Bryn Mawr, PA. Color photos, various personal and professional correspondence, press clippings, postcards of New Mexico, brochures, playbill, bulletins, paper place mats, G. S. notes. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Burnand Gaston Burnand. Personal and professional correspondence, typed outline, G. S. notes, folders relating to specific projects, address lists, book catalog pages. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Angleterre England: G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts, press clippings, typed transcript (radio), letter (Christophe Calthrop to Paul Blanchart), book catalog pages, typed bibliography. England - Authors XXth: Press clippings, programs, typed transcripts (radio), periodicals, individual folders (personalities and one general), book and journal excerpts, newsletter, book catalog pages, tickets and maps (to dress rehearsal, Théâtre Boulogne-Billancourt), G. S. notes. England - Authors: Individual folders (personalities), press clippings, book and journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio). (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Angleterre - Auteurs XXe (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Angleterre - Auteurs (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Ballet Press clippings, typed transcript (radio), periodical, individual folders relating to the ballet world (personalities, companies, etc.), journal excerpts, book advertisement pages. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Bardot Brigitte Bardot. Press clippings (generally more photos than text), periodical, journal excerpts. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Loleh Bellon Press clippings, programs, periodicals. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Tristan Bernard Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, typed transcripts (radio), one-act texts, periodicals, programs, typed essays (articles from an edited work on theatre?). (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Sarah Bernhardt 1844-1923 Press clippings, programs, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio), photo copies of documents relating to S. Bernhardt, book catalog pages, journal excerpt. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pologne Poland. Personal and professional correspondence, B&W photo, guidebooks, G. S. notes, press clippings, cards of residence (hotel documentation), telegrams, invitations (to G. S. from the French ambassador to Poland), plane ticket, business cards, typed itinerary proposals/price quotes, conference invitations and announcements. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Bibliographie Bibliography. Note cards relating a chronology of theatre history (French), press clippings, book catalog and advertisement pages, G. S. notes, newsletters/P.R. releases, journal subscription form, bookstore and publisher catalogs. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Caen Personal and professional correspondence, programs, newsletter, press clippings, theatre tickets, periodicals, publications of TMC (Théâtre Maison de Caen). (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Chine China. Press clippings, notes, journal and book excerpts, book advertisements. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cinéma - E Foreign Cinema (Étranger). Press clippings, newsletter (Club des Amis de Preuves), book advertisement, review, individual folders on foreign cinema personalities. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Cinéma - F French Cinema (Français). Press clippings, journal and book excerpts, individual folders on french cinema personalities. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Cirque (dossier rouge) Circus (red dossier). Typed manuscripts with corrections (2 chapters of Histoire du Cirque and an encyclopedia contribution), periodical, press clippings, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts, typed articles or transcripts, book advertisements, bookstore catalog pages, professional correspondence, photocopies (articles, program), bibliographies, an invitation to a joint French-Soviet function/exposition, individual folders relating to circus in general, personalities, and countries. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Cirque - Music Hall Circus - Music Hall. Press clippings, program, postcards, book and journal excerpts. The subject matter here relates more to actual Music Halls than the circus. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Cirque: Tome I Circus I and II: Photocopy of a book, in two sections. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Cirque: Tome II (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Comédie Française Press clippings, brochure (Bibliothèque Nationale - an exposition for the Tricentenary of the Comédie Française), programs, G. S. notes, newsletters, journal excerpts, excerpt of an auction catalog, printed biographical notecard, periodicals. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Comédiens - Généralités, Écoles Actors - Generalities, Schools. Press clippings, correspondence (from Jean Perimony), notecards, typed manuscripts/transcripts (anecdotes of Max Jacob and Franc-Nohain ?), book and journal excerpts, G. S. notes, periodical, exhibition catalog/booklet of the Musée Goya (Portraits d'Artistes Contemporains du Spectacle; 1964). (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Critique Press clippings, G. S. notes, book and journal excerpts, bookstore and publisher catalogs, periodical. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Décorateurs Decorators. Press clippings, individual folders on many personalities, book catalog and advertisement pages, journal excerpts, pamphlet (about Caspar Neher, in German). (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Dumas - Théâtre Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, G. S. notes, typed transcript (radio), typed manuscript, photocopy of correspondence (to Alexandre Dumas), play texts (printed by Michel Lévy frères, Éditeurs), typed reviews, booklet ( Don Juan de Marana ou La Chute d'un Ange, Drame en Dix Tableaux, Raconté par Robert Macaire et Bertrand, 1836), book catalog pages, typed manuscript with corrections (for an article?). (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Dumas (dossier jaune) Dumas (yellow dossier):Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, book/publisher advertisement, typed manuscripts (one with handwritten corrections), G. S. notes, handwritten manuscripts with notes (not in G. S.'s handwriting). Dumas (red dossier): Press clippings, book and journal excerpts (some of which are inscribed to G. S.), periodical (inscribed), several books and booklets ranging in date from 1845 to 1884. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Dumas (dossier rouge) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Espagne Spain. Individual folders (personalities, plus one general), press clippings, book and journal excerpts, typed transcipts (radio), book catalog and advertisement pages, newsletter (Club des Amis des Preuves), G. S. notes. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Festivals Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcript. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Garbo Greta Garbo. Two typed manuscripts - one with corrections (a translation by Patricia Sigaux of Nona Coxhead's work, Greta Garbo ). (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Genève Geneva. Publisher catalogs (some printed and some typed, mostly of Edito Service S.A.), individual folders on people and businesses, much professional correspondence, book advertisement, G. S. notes, press clippings, photocopies, business documents, minutes of a meeting (Librairie Hachette). (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Hébertot Jacques Hébertot. Program with notes, press clippings, periodical. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Histoire de la Presse History of Journalism. Typed supplement, periodicals, press clippings, printed biographical note cards, pamphlet with inserts (Centre de Formation des Journalistes), book and journal excerpts, individual folders on different French and American newspapers, G. S. notes. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Historiens-Critiques Historians-Critics. Book and journal excerpts, G. S. notes, individual folders relating to critics, professional correspondence (from Charles Chaplin Film Corporation to René Jeanne), typed biography of Georges Lerminier by G. S., typed manuscript relating to the life and death of Nepveu-Degas, bibliography of Jacques Polieri. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Humour-Th. Complements (?) Typed manuscript with corrections, press clippings, professional correspondence (from la Maison des Enfants to G. S.), book excerpt, G. S. notes. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Ibsen I Henrik Ibsen. I: Exhibition catalog with notes (Bibliothèque Nationale), typed manuscript, book and journal excperts, photocopy of journal excerpts, press clippings, G. S. notes. II: Individual folders on works, typed manuscript with corrections, typed manuscript, programs, invitations to plays, transcript (radio), G. S. notes, periodicals. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Ibsen II (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Jacky Jacky Sigaux. Press clippings, an artist's biography of Jacky Sigaux with specific information regarding Le Sea-Side Rendez-Vous, periodicals, season program (Café Théâtre de la Graine), letters from Jacky Sigaux. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Jouvet Louis Jouvet. G. S. notes, program, press clippings, photocopy of professional correspondence (from Théâtre Louis Jouvet to Claude Aveline), journal excerpts, a publication of the Comédie Champs-Élysées Théâtre Louis Jouvet, book advertisement. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Kanters Robert Kanters. Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Labiche-Documentation Eugène Labiche. G. S. notes, book advertisements, correspondence signed Eugène Labiche, photographs, typed manuscript with corrections, correspondence signed Claude Pichois, other correspondence (signatures illegible), book excerpt, photocopies of professional correspondence (from one of the French interior ministries to Labiche), typed list of collaborators, typed bibliographies of Labiche works (with notes), press clippings, typed chronology with corrections, typed transcript (newspaper). (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Labiche-Chh 1-5 Chh 1-5: Typed and handwritten manuscripts with corrections, book excerpt. Chh 6 à 9: Book advertisement, book excerpt, typed and handwritten manuscripts. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Labiche-Chh 6 à 9 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Labiche Eugène Labiche. Typed and handwritten manuscripts, program, individual folders, small book (a publication of la Comédie Française, about Labiche), G. S. notes, press clippings, invitation to a play. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Labiche-Oeuvres-Chron. I Works-Chron. I. Individual folders on different works, handwritten and typed copies of letters and newspaper articles, G. S. notes, journal excerpt, press clippings, typed manuscripts, book advertisement, invitation to special performance of a play, programs, photocopy of a book (La Grammaire by Alphonse Leveaux), periodicals, production photos (b&w). (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Labiche-Correspondance Labiche - Correspondence. Labiche-related correspondence reproduced in chronological form, original handwritten letters dating from 1800's. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Labiche-TV Bound typed scripts of television productions with handwritten notes (La Famille de l'Horloge and La Chaine Anglaise -adaptation de G. S.), press clippings, G. S. notes. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Le Grain de Sable 3 typed manuscripts of Le Grain de Sable (1 with handwritten corrections, 1 marked "3ième révison", and 1 marked "inédit" and "Noël - Noël"). (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Lemarchand II (Généralités) Jacques Lemarchand. Press clippings, typed manuscript or article (by Lemarchand). (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Leningrad 19 - 29 Sept 1973 A brief travel diary/agenda for G. S.'s Sept. '73 trip to Leningrad, G. S. notes, business cards, postcards, various personal correspondence (of which some are signed Eléonore, T. Voronova, or Ella), professional correspondence (from the Ministère d'Affaires Étrangères and the Université de Leningrad), programs (in Russian), tickets (in Russian), book (in Russian, a gift of Voronova), b&w photographs (of theater productions - Soviet), book (Silhouettes of Leningrad, mostly b&w images of Leningrad). (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Les Chiens Enragés Materials here relate to G. S.'s book, Les Chiens Enragés. G. S. notes, periodicals, press clippings, typed transcript (newspaper, in Italian), journal excerpts, book advertisement, typed reviews, various correspondence (of which some are signed Pauline Valmy, Gaston Picard, or Julien Durand). (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Livres Qui... Gén. Books That... Gen. Press clipping, personal correspondence (to G. S.), professional correspondence (Edito-Service and contributors), G. S. notes, various documentation relating to a proposed edited series entitled "Les Livres Qui Ont Fait le Monde." (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Lucien Guitry Auction catalog pages, G. S. notes, typed manuscript with corrections, correspondence (from P. Billard with G. S. notes), book and journal excerpts (including photocopies), press clippings. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Lyon Press clippings. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Maiakowski Vladimir Vladimirovitch Maiakowski. Press clippings, periodical, journal excerpts, book advertisement page. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Marceau Felicien Marceau. Individual folders (of works), journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio), press clippings, a printed note/solicitation (from Éditions Gallimard about the creation of a fund for l'épée de l'Academie Française for F. Marceau.), G. S. notes, programs, invitation to a special presentation (A Nous de Jouer), ticket, periodicals. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Marionnettes Press clippings, book excerpt, book catalog page, publication/brochure of the Marrionetteatern. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Marivaux Pierre Carlet de Chamblain de Marivaux. Individual folders (works), press clippings, book and journal excerts, G. S. notes, a publication of La Comédie Française (about Marivaux), typed transcripts (radio), book advertisement pages, photocopy of typed manuscript (Sur La Commère), a publication of the Festival d'Automne à Paris '73, play advertisement, program, typed information and documentation of Jeune Théâtre National (cast list, season schedule). (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Mélodrames (dossier gris) Melodramas (grey dossier). Photocopy of book (le Jugement de Salomon Mélodrame en trois actes, mélé de chants et de danse. L. C. Caignez, 1802 ), G. S. notes, book with notes (l'Homme du peuple drame en trois actes et en prose par MM. Dumersan et Gabriel. Musique de M. Alex. Piccini, Ballet de M. Anatole, Décorations de M. LeFèvre. J. N. Barba, Éditeur 1829 (with copious handwritten notes bound with the volume), two booklets (play texts), more play texts from the 1800s - publications of Calman Lèvy Éditeur (ancienne maison Michel Lèvy Frères). (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Mélodrame (dossier jaune) Melodrama (yellow dossier). Packet of G. S. note cards, typed manuscript, photocopy of typed manuscript, journal excerpts, periodical, typed transcript (radio), booklet (L'évolution du théâtre social en France de 1750 á 1850 ), photocopy of book with notes (Les Origines du Mélodrame Français à la fin du XVIIIe siècle). (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Metteurs en Scène E Directors/Producers-Foreign (Étranger). Press clippings, G. S. notes, individual folders on different directors/producers, programs, typed manuscripts/articles, journal excerpt. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Metteurs en Scène Directors/Producers. Individual folders on different directors/producers; journal excerpts, personal correspondence (assumed to be from Xavier de Courville), program, printed biographical note card, personal correspondence (J. Richer ?), G. S. notes, advertisement gimic for exposition of Polieri in the shape of a bookmark. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Arthur Miller Press clippings, book and journal excerpts, periodical, individual folders (on works), programs, book advertisement, typed supplement to periodical, periodicals. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Molière (born: Jean-Baptiste Poquelin). Greeting card, auction catalog of Molière-related materials (collection of M. Robert Manuel), book and journal excerpts, press clippings, G. S. notes, invitiation to a play (Les Femmes Savants), typed chronology of life and works, book advertisement, book catalog pages, individual folders (on works). (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Moreno 1871 1948 Marguerite Moreno. (born: Lucie Marie Marguerite Monceau). G. S. notes, journal excerpts, photocopy of journal excerpt with corrections, periodical, typed manuscripts,notes (author unknown). (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Monte-Cristo Professional correspondence (from Etienne Cluzal, Éditions Gallimard, or Société des Gens de Lettres de France), G. S. notes, handwritten manuscripts, journal excerpt, typed manuscripts with corrections, typed manuscripts, photocopy of a book, excerpt of bulletin by Cluzel, book catalog page. (Box 11, Folder 7)